Guide to the Wallace Gendron papers 1941-1945
Whitman College and Northwest Archives
Wallace Gendron papers
1941-1945
Whitman College and Northwest Archives 345 Boyer Avenue Walla Walla, WA 99362 Archives@whitman.edu https://library.whitman.edu/archives/
Gendron, Wallace
WCMss.035
3.0 linear feet 8 boxes
Aerial photographs depicting Allied operations in Europe during World War II and personal memorabilia collected by Wallace Gendron. Correspondence and photos of Walla Walla Air Base.
Collection is open for research.
Donated to Whitman College Archives and Special Collections by Wallace Gendron between 1989 and 1991. The accession number is retro-0093.
Born March 4, 1923 in Berlin, N.H., Mr. Gendron served in the U.S. Army Air Forces during World War II. He moved to Portland, OR after the war and was a salesman and manager for several companies. He married Alicia Frances Niebergall, a native of Walla Walla whom he met while stationed at Walla Walla Air Base, in 1945. He died June 19, 2001.
Photographs of World War II (1941-45) era, featuring aftermath photographs of bombing raids carried out by Army Air Force pilots. Gendron, an Army Air Force photographer, would follow up on bombing raids, showing the results of air attacks on German targets. Personal memorabilia collected by Gendron during his three years of service, including a survival kit issued to soldiers in the event they are captured. Also includes orrespondence and photographs of Walla Walla Air Base.
United States. Army Air Forces. Air Division, 2nd
Military; Military
- Photographs of damage to German towns, factories, and other military targets during World War II, 1941-1945; 1
  - Altenbeken Viaduct (1 photo), Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Amberg Ord. Depot (2 photos), Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Arnsberg (4 photos), Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aschaffenburg (9), Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aschenslenben (8), Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Banburg R.R (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bayreuth (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bernburg (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bielefeld (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bingen (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Boblingen (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bochum (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bottrop Oil (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bremen (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Brunswick (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clausthal-Zellerfeld (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Cologne/Gremburg (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Cologne Cathedral (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Dortmund Coke (7), Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dulman G.A.F. Fuel (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Dulmen (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Eipzig (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Eisenach (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Erfurt Bindersleben (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Emmenich Oil (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Erfurt/Nord (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Erfurt Radar Inst. (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Eschwege (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Fallersleben (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Flak Bat. (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Frankfurt (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Friedrichshafen (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fulda (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Furth (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Gaggenan (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Gardelegen (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Gelsenkirchen Oil (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Gera (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - German Farm House (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Giebelstadt (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Giessen (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Gotha (15), Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Gottingen (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Gutersloh (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Guttingen (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Halberstadt (10), Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Halle (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Hallendorf (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Hamburg (20), Undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Hamm (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Hambur Deutsche Petrol (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Hanau (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Hanau Dunlop (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Hanau Henaeus (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hanover [Hannover] (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Hanburg (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Hanburg Oil (8), Undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Hemmingstedt Oil (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Hildesheim (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Hitzacker Oil (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Hopsten (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Ijmuiden (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Jena-Carl Ziess (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Kaiserslautern (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Karlsruhe (8), Undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Kassel Altenbuata Areo Eng. (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Kassel Henschel Works (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Kassel Loco-Works (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Kassel RR Shops (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Kassel RR Station (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Kassel Walpau Fighter Assem (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Kaiserslautern (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Kiel (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Kitzingen (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Koblenz Mosel (10), Undated (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Kothen (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Kriensen (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Krummel Ammo (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Laacher See (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Lachen/Speyerdorf (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Leipzig-Erla (11), Undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Leuna (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Leverkeusen (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Lagendleroch (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Lutzkendorf (7), Undated (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Magdeburg (3), Undated (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Memmingen (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Merseburg (8), Undated (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Meschede (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Nurnburg M.A.N. (15), Undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Minden (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Misburg (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Munich (13), Undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Munster (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Munster (Canal) (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Negatives (Box 5)
  - Negatives (Box 8)
  - Neumarkt (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Neuwied (2), Undated (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Nordhausen (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Northampton, UK (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Oldenburg (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Oschersleben (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Osnabruck (5), Undated (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Padernborn (4), Undated (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Pforzheim (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Plantlumne (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Plauen (6), Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Rastatt (9), Undated (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Remagen Br (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Rheine (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Rheine Bridges (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Roth (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rothenburg (4), Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Rothensee (4), Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Rudesheim (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Saarbrucken (8), Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Schulan Oil (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Schaffenburg (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Siegen (4), Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sinzig (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Sleaford (UK) (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Soest (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Spaulding (UK) (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Speyer (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Speyer Bridge (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stade (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Stenkrade Oil (5), Undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Trier Bridge (1), Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ulm (5), Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Vegesack (3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Waggum (3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wenzendorf (3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Wesermunde (4), Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Wetzlar (3), Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Wilhelmshaven (14), Undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Wurzburg (7), Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Zietz (10), Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Zwischenahn (2), Undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Memorabilia from WW II service; pamphlets, publications, photos of various aircraft of the period. Walla Walla Airbase photos and memos, 1941-1945; 2
  - Pocket Atlas of the World. W. & A.K. Johnston Ltd. London, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - The 8th Sees England. Jack H. Bozurg, ed. and pub., 1946 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - The Story of the U.S. Army Air Force by Jim Ray, 1945 (Box 5)
  - Target: Germany. The U.S. Army Air Force official story of the 8th Bomber Command's first year over Europe, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Technical Manual. Interpretation of Aerial Photographs. War Dept., 1942 December 31 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - 100 Best True Stories of World War II. Wm H. Wise and Co., Inc., 1945 (Box 3)
  - The War's Best Photographs. Odhams Press Ltd., Undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - New Testament. Roman Catholic Version (U.S. Army), 1942 (Box 5)
  - The Destruction of Germany Through Air Power. Aero Camera and Pub. Co., Undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - The Battle of Britain August-October 1940. Ministry of Information on behalf of the Air Ministry, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Prayer Book for Catholic Servicemen. The National Catholic Community Service., 1943 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - My Military Missal. Edited by Father Stedman, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - A Short Guide to Great Britain. War and Navy Dept., Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - French Phrase Book, 1943 September 28 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Of Dirty Stories. By Daniel A. Lord, S.J., 1935 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - A Salute to the Men in Service. Daniel A. Lord, S.J., 1942 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - If You Should Be Captured These Are Your Rights. War Dept. Pamphlet No. 21-27, 1944 May 16 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - British Edition of "Yank" Vol. 3, No. 48, 1945 May 18 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Norwich Cathedral, by E.C. LeGrice, F.R.P.S., Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Salvo: Rosewell Army Air Field. V. 4 #13 (22 September 1945), V. 4 #12 (15 September 1945), V. 4 #10 (1 September 1945), V. 4 #9 (25 August 1945), V. 4 #14 (29 September 1945), V. 4 #11 (8 September 1945), 1945 August 25-1945 September 29 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Air Force. The Official Service Journal. Article: Aerial Mapping for Invasion, 1945 September (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Walla Walla Eagle Vol. 2 No. 1, 1943 June 29 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - The Stars and Stripes. London Ed., Vol. 5 No. 158, "Germany Quits.", 1945 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Boston Sunday Advertiser Pictorial Review. Memorial Ed. To F. D. Roosevelt, 1882-1945., 1945 April 15 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Magazine Article on Aerial War Photography, Undated (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Program: Skirts. American Musical Adventure in 15 Scenes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Magazine Article: The Fightingest Fortress Suzy-Q, Boeing News, 1943 March (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Typed Copy: An English Girl's Lament, Undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Issue of Daily Bulletin #448, 1945 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Duffel Bag Content List for W. Gendron, 1945 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Propaganda Material Dropped over Germany, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Sets of Orders for W.R. Gendron, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Dwight D. Eisenhower, Supreme Headquarters Allied Expeditionary Forces, note to "Soldiers, Salutes, & Airmen of the Allied Expeditionary Forces!" Invasion of Europe, 1944 June (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Photos of Wycomba Abbey, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - The Honor Legion, by Francis P. Schiavone, 1st pub. 1917, Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Pocket Reference Guide: Army, Navy, Marine Corps Insignia, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Postcard Pocket: 2. Coronation of King George VI & Queen Elizabeth, Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - U.S. Army Air Forces Post Cards, Undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Stars and Stripes, Vol. 5 No. 15, 1944 November 18 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "The Wings of War," National Geographic Vol. 185, No. 3, 1994 March (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Map of Germany Highlighting Areas of Bomb Strikes, Undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Packet of 6 Photos, War's End in Europe, General Wm. Kepner and Hodges Saying Goodbye to Staff., 1944 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Victorian Memorial in Front of Buckingham Palace, 1945 February 2 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "This is the Army," London Photograph of stage show, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - 5 Photos: Sporting events in England During WWII, Undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Photos of Ceremonies Returning Air Base to England after War, Undated (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Photos of unidentified Servicemen, Undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Wallace Gendron I.D. cards from Days at WW Airbase & Postcards from Family, Undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - B-24 Aircraft photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Photos of Aircraft Shot Down, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Various Photos of European Theatre, Including Some from D-Day and Liberation of Holland, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photos of P-47 Fighter Aircraft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Dropping Supplies in Holland", Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Glider Troops: D-day, France, 1944 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Four Photos of B-17 Aircraft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "B-24's on a Mission", Undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Three Photos: B-24 Going Down and Crash in France, Undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Two photos of P-38 Aircraft, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Thirteen Photos of Aircraft in Formation, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Nine Photos of Jimmy Stewart, Movie Actor, Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Three Photos of Smoke Screen Used by the Germans to Camouflage Targets, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Two Photos of Incendiary Bombs, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Six Photos of Vapor Trails, Undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ketteringtor Hall, Headquarter of 2nd Air Division, 8th Air Force, Norwich, U.K., Undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - 50th Anniversary Booklet, Boeing B-17 Flying Fortress, Undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photo of P-39 "only fighter plane U.S. had at time of Pearl Harbor", Undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Dorothy Ann, Undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - WWII Aerial Damage Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Invasion of Normandy, 1944 June 6 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photo of WWII after the Surrender, Inspection of a German Airdrome for Damage, Photo of Smoking Damage, Aerial Photo of City, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photo of Gliders, WWII Damage, Aerial Photo, Airbase Photo, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photo of C-47, Distance Plane Photo, Aerial Photo, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Christmas Photos on Base, Aerial Photo, Plane Take-off, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photos of Motor Pool and Drivers, Damage Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Visit from General "Hap" Arnold, Miscellaneous Aerial Views, Undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photos of Awards Ceremony, Inspection of the MPs, Photo of B-24 and Crew, Undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Photo of Tail of AB24, American Troops in Holland Behind Fleeing German Troops, Dropping Supplies, Undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Photos of Damage after the Surrender WWII, Miscellaneous Damage Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ball Bearing Plant in Germany, Taxi to the Runway for a Trip over Germany, Undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - German V-2 Rockets, Bomb Centers in England, Undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - 80th Bomb Division, 317 Bomb Squad, W.W. Army Air Base, Boardman Bombing Range, Practice Bombing, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Walla Walla Army Air Base, Combat Crew #440, Undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Army Air Base Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Walla Walla Air Base, B-25 Mitchell, Accompanying Letter from Alfred McVay to Sergeant W. M. Mack, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - B-17 Crash on Blue Mountains, Undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Base Photo Section Building and Crew, Undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Walla Walla Photographers and Photos in Blue Mountains, Undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - George Montgomery (Actor) and His Mother in front of C-47, Walla Walla, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Ann Southern (Actress) at McCaw Hospital, Walla Walla, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Walla Walla Baseball Game and Accompanying Newspaper Clips, 1943 June (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Aircraft Insignia, Undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Walla Walla at Retreat, Wallace Gendron in Publicity Shot with Two Women and One Sailor, with Accompanying Letter, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Walla Walla Air Base, Newspaper Articles, 1943, 1991, 1992, Various dates (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - General Peck, Commanding Officer of Walla Walla Air Base, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - James Cagney in Walla Walla, Undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Walla Walla Base Chapel, Undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Trainer, Walla Walla Air Base, Undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Walla Walla Retreat, Ten Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Walla Walla Mill Creek Picnic, Undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - B-17 and Crew, Walla Walla, Undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Walla Walla Aircrafts, Undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Walla Walla USO Dance, Five Photos, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Walla Walla Sign Regarding Hitler, Undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Walla Walla Exploding Bomb, 1943 April 26 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Awarding of Purple Heart, Walla Walla, Undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Firing Range, Mill Creek, Circa 1940 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Suzy-Q, Airplane at Walla Walla, with Boeing News Article, 1943 March 24 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - England: Volleyball, One-man Suli, Norwich, Tea Time, King's College, John Touchette, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Lyons Property, Mill Creek, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Wally Gendron, Sergeant Phil Lipmon, and unidentified soldier, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - State Capitol of Colorado, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Performance and Dance for the Army, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "The Circular Spectrum", Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Bomber Formation on Its Way to Target in Germany, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Norwich Castle, 1943 December 22 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - English Showgirls Sitting on the Wing of a P-51, Undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Second Air Division Office Personnel (3 Photos), Undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Buckingham Palace, England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Inspection at a Bomber Group Base, Undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Photo Crew, Second Air Division, "Two Years Together," England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - English Boy Adopted as the Mascot of the Second Air Division, Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - General Kepner Honoring a Local Dame, with the Second Air Division Choir, Undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Oil Refinery in Germany, Undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Airplane Crash, Undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - St. Paul Cathedral, Undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Aerial Photo Showing Damage to France, 1944 January 14 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - D-Day: Gliders Towed into France to Cut off German Supplies to Normandy, Undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - German Air Field, Undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Photo Reconnaissance after Mission, 1944 March (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - General Hodges with Staff, Undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Portrait Photos of Major Edwin Reid and General Jimmie Doolittle, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Tea Time Truck, England (with negative), Undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - B-24 Shot Down Over Hamburg, Germany (3 Photos), Undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Preparing a New Assignment, Undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Gotha, Germany, Home of the Leica Camera Factory, Undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - German Air Field, France, Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Oil Field and Refinery in Ploiesti, Romania, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Bombing Berlin, Undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - German Fighter Squadron Field Near the Coast, Undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - B-24 Shot Down in France (3 Photos), Undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Aerial Photograph of Damages to Hermmigstedt, Karlsruhe, Nordhausen, and Other Unidentified Cities, Undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - At the Race Tracks, Undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Party for "Beaver Bill", Undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Officer at Lowry Air Base, Denver Colorado, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Walla Walla Airbase Church, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Orphans, England, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Aerial Photographs of Damages to Ploiesti, Romania (19 Photos), Undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Soldiers Marching Through the Streets of England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Soldiers Receiving Medals at Decoration Ceremony, Undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Officers Receiving Medals at Base, Undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Major Cassidy, Captain Florence, and 5 Unidentified Officers, Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Totem Pole, Undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - 1942 Penna Ford, Undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Armament Laboratory, Wooden Door, Undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Western Flight Training Commander's Twins, Roswell N. M. Air Base, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - A Soldier's Wedding, Undated (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Paintings, Undated (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Abandoned Pottery Shop, Undated (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Schawillie and Redmand Leading Their Cameras, 1943 April 5 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Franklyn Stokes, New Haven, Connecticut, Undated (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Stock Yards, Horshem, England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - P. 39 Bell Air Cobra, Lowry Field, Denver, Colorado, Undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Typical Payday at the Second Air Division, Undated (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Tea Time, England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Lt. McCormick from Colorado Springs, Undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Taking Time Off to Help a Local Farmer, 1944 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Press Box, Football Game, England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - "The Boys in the Photo Lab" and Major, Head of the Photo Lab, Undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - England: Max Melcher, Christmas Time at the Local Orphanage, Taking the Orphan Kids on an Outing, London, Undated (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - England: Honor Guard, General Doolittle on a Visit, English WACs, Undated (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Neighborhood Damaged by War, Belgium, Undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - A G.I. Wedding in England, Undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Captain Hawkins Inspecting an Underground Storage Unit After a Raid, France, Undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Inspection at Kettringham Hall, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - B-77 Model, with Explanation and Description, Undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Ketteringham Hall Floor Plan, Undated (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - England: St. Theresa's Church, Norwich, London, Flixton Estate, King's College, etc., 1943 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Mt. Rushmore National Memorial, Undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Johnny Touchett and Wallace Gendron, Base Photo, Undated (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Blue Mountains, Walla Walla, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - "Coming Home," Black Forest, Germany, Undated (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Combat Crew #109, Walla Walla Army Air Force, 1945 March 14 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Walla Walla Air Base, 1943 April 7 (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Interior of Kitchen in the Mess Hall, Undated (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Air Force Insignia, Undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Upper Mill Creek, Undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
- Unidentified Photographs; Gendron's Magazines, Postcards, Identifications, and Ephemera, 1942-1976; 3
  - Unidentified Photos of Officers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Photos of Officers (continued), Undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Unidentified Scenery Photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Unidentified Scenery Photos (continued), Undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Unidentified Photos of a Party, Undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Unidentified Aerial Photos, Undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Unidentified Negatives, Undated (Box 4, Folder 25)